Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy, Assistant to the Provost; Records ua680.001
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Nelson A. Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy, Assistant to the Provost Records
1980-2004
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Nelson A. Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy, Assistant to the Provost
ua680.001
2.4 cubic ft.
This collection consists of the administrative records of the Assistant to the Provost of the Nelson A. Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of a small number of select folders noted below.
Acquisition Information
Jerry Parker donated his records to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in December 2010.
Biographical Sketch
The Nelson A. Rockefeller College of Public Affairs was established April 22, 1982, named to honor the contributions to New York State government of Governor Nelson Rockefeller who served from 1959-1973. The creation of the new college signified State University of New York (SUNY) at Albany President Vincent O’Leary’s (1977-1990) attempt to give additional academic and institutional weight to graduate programs of the University most closely tied to public policy in New York at a time when the University was reemphasizing its roots as a public policy institution. The new college initially brought together the School of Criminal Justice, the Graduate School of Public Affairs, and the School of Social Welfare under the umbrella of the Rockefeller College of Public Affairs. Each of the individual schools retained its dean, but the Office of the Provost, and the new position of Provost of Rockefeller College, was created to lobby for and coordinate the activities of all three schools. In 1986, the School of Information Science and Policy was merged into Rockefeller College. The provost was also the designated director of the Nelson A. Rockefeller Institute of Government, an independent think tank reporting to the SUNY chancellor, set up to study public policy problems in New York.
The Assistant to the Provost was responsible for overseeing use of the buildings on the Downtown Campus, organizing various events such as Commencement, Alumni Awards Dinners, and Dedications, and for overseeing the Rockefeller College Art Collection. Jerry Parker held the position from 1981-2000. From 2000 until his retirement in 2010, Parker continued to work as an administrator at the University at Albany organizing events on the Downtown Campus.
In 2000 Rockefeller College was restructured, each of the constituent schools (Criminal Justice, Public Affairs, Social Welfare and Information Science and Policy) once again became independent schools under their individual deans reporting to the new University at Albany position of Provost and Vice President for Academic Affairs, and the position of Provost of Rockefeller College was eliminated. The Graduate School of Public Affairs changed its name to The Nelson A. Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy, thus preserving the honor to Nelson Rockefeller, if not the original intended function of the College.
See the records of the Graduate School of Public Affairs (UA-680) for a full description of the creation and growth of that school/college.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the administrative records of the Assistant to the Provost of Rockefeller College created or collected by Jerry Parker. The bulk of the records are budget reports, correspondence, meeting notes, and photographs and newspaper clippings related to college events. During processing, the archivist retained the original folder titles assigned by the records’ creator with the following exceptions: “Creation of Rockefeller College-administration and structure” was originally two separate folders named “Organization and History of Rockefeller College” and “Rockefeller College Memorabilia.” As the contents of the folders were similar (administrative correspondence from the early years of Rockefeller College) they were combined and given a new title that was more indicative of the contents. In Series Two, “Provost’s Office Inventory Account 83001” was renamed “Rockefeller College Art Collection Inventory” for clarification purposes.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Both Series 1 and 2 are arranged alphabetically.
Africana Studies; College administrators; Budget--New York (State); Campus planning--New York (State); Commencement ceremonies; Albany (N.Y.); Photographs; Clippings; Correspondence; Files by subject; Newsletters; Financial Records; Budgets; UAlbany Schools & Colleges; Parker, Jerry; Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy; State University of New York at Albany; Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy--Office of the Assistant to the Provost
- Administrative Files, 1980-2000; Undated; 1; 1.66 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains budget files, reports, organizational charts and information, downtown campus planning information, and meeting notes of various departments, councils, and committees. Correspondence between the Provost, Assistant to the Provost, other University Administrators and outside parties are interspersed throughout these files.
  - Budget, 1993-1996 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 1-2)
  - 1984-1985 Budget Document-[RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - 1985-1986 Budget Document-[RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
  - 1986-1987 Budget Document, Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
  - 1987-1988 Budget Document, Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
  - 1988-1989 Budget Document, Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
  - Budget Panel Subcommittee, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
  - Budget Request, 1999-2000 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 9-10)
  - Continuing Education Facility for Downtown Campus (Levitt Room, DR 313), 1980; 1983-1985 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 11)
  - Creation of Rockefeller College, Administration and Structure-[RESTRICTED], 1980-1982; 1984-1986 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 12-16)
  - Downtown Campus Administrator, 1983; 1986 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 17)
  - Downtown Campus Long-Range Planning Committee, 1989; 1991; 1993 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 18)
  - Faculty Council, 1989-1991 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 19)
  - Faculty Council 1985-Spring 1989, 1985-1989, 1993 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 20-21)
  - Five Year Plan for 1984-1989 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 22)
  - Five Year Plan for 1985-1990 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 23)
  - Five Year Plan for 1990-1994 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 24)
  - Levitt Fund, 1984; 1988; 1993-2001 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 25)
  - Levitt Room, 1983; 1986-1987; 1989 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 26)
  - Levitt Room Dedication, 1987 (Cassette 1)
  - Materials for Presentation to Budget Panel Subcommittee, 1991 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - Milne Fund, 1992-1998 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 2-3)
  - Organizational Charts (Rockefeller College), 1997; 2000; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
  - Planning Memoranda, 1991 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
  - Planning Memorandum 1987-1992, Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
  - Presentation Outline for Budget Panel Subcommitte, 1991 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
  - Renaming Downtown Campus Buildings, 1981-1984; 1986; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
  - Report for Karen Hitchcock on PDP Deficit, 1996; 1998 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 9-10)
  - Rockefeller College 1995-1996 Budget Reduction Plan (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 11)
  - Rockefeller College 1995-1996 Budget Reduction Plan-2nd version (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 12)
  - Rockefeller College Budget Requests, 1988; 1989-1990 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 13)
  - Rockefeller College Bylaws, 1981; 1989-1990; 1992; 1996; 1998 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 14)
  - Rockefeller College Contingency Plan Reports, 1995 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 15)
  - Rockefeller College Dean’s Meetings Notes, 1991-1995; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 16-17)
  - Rockefeller College Department Meetings, 1983-1984; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 18)
  - Rockefeller College Strategic Plan, 1996 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 19)
  - Second Level Review Committee-[RESTRICTED], 1983-1991; 1995-1998; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 20-21)
  - Strategic Visions, Accomplishments and Resource Priorities, 1993 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 22)
  - Strategic Visions, Accomplishments and Resource Priorities, 1994 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 23)
- Subject Files, 1982-2004; Undated; 2; 0.74 cubic ft.
  This series contains information related to University events such as Commencement and Convocation, Alumni dinners, dedications of various rooms and buildings on the downtown campus (including the Dewey Library), a history of the downtown campus, its buildings, and the graduate schools incorporated into Rockefeller College, as well as information and inventories of the Rockefeller College Art Collection. This series also includes a number of promotional and informational publications created by Rockefeller College, including the Colleges’ newsletter—RC Report. Additionally there are a number of photographs (prints, contact sheets, and negatives), as well as newspaper clippings related to events held at Rockefeller College and one audio cassette tape.
  - 1995 Alumni Awards Dinner Photos, Undated (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Alumni Awards Dinner, 1984-1999 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 25-26)
  - Alumni Reception 2000 Photos, Undated (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Banquet Photos, 1997 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Banquet Photos, 1998 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Commencement 1993 Photos, Undated (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Convocation/Commencement Photos, 1982-1984; 1992; Undated (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Dedication of Fosnick Room, Milne 200 Photos, 1995 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Dewey Library Dedication, 1987-1988 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Distinguished Alumni Photos 1993, Undated (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Fall Convocation-1983, 1982-1984 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 35-36)
  - NARC Convocation, 1983; Undated (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Rockefeller College Art Collection Inventory, 1992-1994 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Rockefeller College Convocation, 1983 (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Rockefeller College Prints and Paintings, 1984; 1995; 2003-2004; Undated (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Rockefeller College Publications, Undated (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 3-4)
  - RC Reports, 1984-1992 (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Rockefeller College School Histories, Undated (Box 3 (2-Subject Files), Folder 6)